(+91) 7795794208

govardhan.s92@gmail.com

## **Skills Synopsis**

Technical Skills: Angular, React, Typescript, Spring Framework, Java Web services, Node JS, Express JS,

Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, MEAN Stack, Mongodb, Redis, Elastic search, SQL, Webpack, Grunt, Karma, Nginx, Jenkins, Docker, CI/CD, VSO, Git, SVN, Photoshop and

more

Domain: IT Consulting, Healthcare, Construction

## **Experience Summary**

I'm a creative professional Full Stack Web Developer with over 5.9 years of experience in latest web design and hosting technologies like AWS, Oracle and Azure Cloud.

Have good exposure in developing single page applications, micro frontends, web portals, hybrid apps, CRM platform apps together with strong understanding of best practices, analytical capabilities, organizational skills and ability to complete a successful implementation.

## **Professional Experience**

# **Dutchview IT, Bangalore SDE II**

Jan 2018 - Present

Dutchview IT believes that when you work smart and efficiently together, the overall job satisfaction will increase and better results will be achieved. They develop innovative software that helps you to do so, by making work processes easier, smarter and more enjoyable. This company was formed from Mobinius Technologies, Bangalore by transferring employees in Aug 2019.

- Was an integral part in all stages of the product development lifecycle.
- Worked on critical features of web apps Real-time data sync, Chat app, Analytics, Performance etc.
- Collaborated with Product Managers, developers and designers of different teams to create rollout plans for different modules.
- Develop REST services for complex calculations, real-time data sync and chat applications.
- Develop Angular and React solutions with authentication, authorisation, routing, templates, directives, services, filters and custom solutions to meet requirements and optimise the performance.
- Validating user actions on the client side and providing responsive feedback.
- Test Driven Development with Jasmine and Jest.
- Automate, Optimise the development process with webpack, jenkins along with CI and CD.

## Cognizant, Bangalore Full Stack Web Developer

Apr 2016 - Dec 2017

Cognizant (NASDAQ-100: CTSH) is a world-leading professional services company, transforming business, operating and IT models for the digital era. Cognizant is an American multinational corporation that provides IT services, including digital, technology, consulting, and operations services. It is headquartered in Teaneck, New Jersey, United States.

- Worked on various products for companies like MICROSOFT and ORACLE marketplace.
- Worked on critical features of web apps Single Sign-on (SSO), Analytics, Performance etc. Collaborated with Product Managers, developers and designers of different teams to create rollout plans for different modules.
- Develop Angular solutions with authentication, authorisation, routing, templates, directives, services, filters and custom solutions to meet requirements and optimise the performance.
- Validating user actions on the client side and providing responsive feedback.
- Unit testing with Karma.
- Develop Node JS based REST services for complex calculations.
- Develop Java based REST services comprising PL/SQL as database.
- Automate, Optimise the development process with webpack, grunt along with CI and CD.
- Enhance the application to native android apps using WebView concept of Cordova.

## Indegene, Bangalore Web Developer

May 2015 - Apr 2016

Indegene offers research and development and management solutions to healthcare and pharmaceutical enterprises. It was founded in 1998 and is based in Bangalore, India and maintains offices internationally.

- Worked on various global brands of companies like PFIZER, GE Healthcare etc.
- Worked with designers for standardising Email and Web Experience of web apps.
- Develop Veeva CRM web app targeting iOS devices like Mac and iPads.
- Develop Native app compatible using XCode with WebView concept for iOS devices.
- Develop Email templates to enhance sales marketing.
- Capture analytics like user clicks, time spent, user interests and many more.
- Cross Browser compatibility testing.

#### **Awards**

Title	Institution
Best Performer of the month	Indegene
Aspire Double Up Award	Indegene
Wah Points, Brownie Points	Cognizant

#### **Publications**

Title	URL
Portfolio	https://govardhan-srinivas.github.io
LinkedIn	https://www.linkedin.com/in/govardhan-srinivas
Blog	https://medium.com/@govardhan.s

## **Excel NPV**

Custom-select-dropdown

https://www.npmjs.com/package/custom-select-dropdown

# **Certifications**

Institution	Course
NIIT, Bangalore	Post Graduation in Java
Code School	Real time web with Node
Cognizant	Frontend Web Developer
Cognizant	Full Stack Web Developer

# **Education**

Institution	Degree
Visvesvaraya Technological University, India	Bachelor of Engineering - 69%
Sarvodaya Pre-university College, Tumkur, India	XII - 78%
B. G National Public School, Bangalore, India	X - 88%